# Daniel Baldassare, PhD

daniel.baldassare@utah.edu linkedin.com/in/dbaldassare99/

Climate scientist with over 7 years of professional and research experience in atmospheric science, climate adaptation planning, remote sensing, machine learning, engineering, and technical report writing. Skilled manager having overseen teams as large as 30 while delivering on complex projects.

## Education

- **Doctor of Philosophy PhD, Atmospheric Science**, *University of Utah*, 2021 2024
- Master of Science MS, Atmospheric Science University of Nevada, Reno, 2019 2020
- Bachelor of Science BS, Geophysics University of California, Davis, 2011 2015

## **Experience**

#### • Climate Scientist

Baldassare Climate Consulting, September 2023 - Present

- o Wrote the NEPA Climate Report for large restoration projects for the USFS and nonprofits.
- Created high-resolution projections of local climate change to meet project resilience regulations.
- Produced estimates of greenhouse gas emissions and changes in carbon storage from proposed actions.
- Assisted climate tech companies with market research and product design.

## Climate Dynamics Research Assistant

University of Utah, Jan 2022 - May 2024

- o Created novel methods for improved climate projections using economics and machine learning.
- o Published multiple first-author papers on climate change, data science, and adaptation.
- o Analyzed terabytes of climate data using Python, machine learning, and cloud computing.
- Worked with a diverse team to meet requirements of a multidisciplinary NSF sponsored project, producing presentations and publications in multiple academic fields.

## Mechanical Engineering Research Assistant

University of Utah, Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- o Designed and implemented machine learning and physics-based wind and flux measurement devices utilizing drone thermal imagery using Python, MATLAB, and cloud computing.
- Established a data pipeline for processing raw infrared data to derive wind speed.

#### Director

Castine Yacht Club, Jun 2020 - Sep 2021 (Seasonal)

- o Managed operations, facilities, hiring, and staff at a yacht club in Maine.
- o Reported to board of directors and oversaw finances and long-term planning.

#### Physics Research Assistant

University of Nevada, Reno, Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

o Processed multiple terabyte-scale atmospheric datasets using Python to produce novel insights into surface level meteorology, resulting in publications.

## • Engineering Research Technician

University of California, Davis, Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

o Designed and implemented a field research campaign, used Python to analyzed resulting data.

#### Geophysics Research Assistant

University of California, Davis, Sep 2014 - Sep 2015